Carmen Ng

Web Developer

An adaptable and motivated individual with a strong understanding of visual communications currently working as a Senior Software Engineer at OpenRice. Over 5 years of web development experience has allowed me to develop strong analytical and problem solving skills. I am eager to continue learning new skills and gain more experience in various areas and languages as I am always striving for self improvement, both professionally and personally.

Hong Kong

in linkedin.com/in/carng

Available via Email

nightlightvisuals.com

github.com/CarNg

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

OpenRice 🛂

09/2019 - Present Hong Kong

- Develop & maintain OpenRice.com and Biz.OpenRice.com as part of the Web Team
- Supervise & manage team members' from overseas offices to ensure high quality, timely delivery of tasks
- Work with other teams, such as Product Design, UI Design, QA, Data Team, in order to complete and release new features and enhancements on a regular basis

Solutions Developer

PCCW Solutions

04/2017 - 09/2019

Hong Kong

- Redesign & develop the frontend (JSP, JavaScript, jQuery and CSS) for clients' existing ERP systems.
- Work directly with BAs to design and develop more user friendly flows and enhancements.
- API connection to existing Oracle E-Business ERP (Java).

Full Stack Developer

RT-Technology Ideas Holding Ltd.

04/2016 - 03/2017

Hong Kong

RT-Technology is behind BabyPOS POS system. They also provide services in web design & development and SEO optimisation.

- Develop & maintain the web platform for BabyPOS.
- Connect BabyPOS' API to clients' online shops allowing live updates between the two.
- Design & develop clients' websites and online shops.
- Design & develop internal sites, such as a management platform for sales team and websites used for marketing.

Contact: Raymond Tse - raymond@babypos.hk

SKILLS

Vue.js Less

Node.js **Bootstrap**

NFT jQuery

PhotoShop React

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Night Light Visuals (2015 - Present)

 Night Light Visuals is my personal branding and portfolio site for my previous and current projects. The website is built using React.js

This Time Around (02/2014 - 02/2015)

'This Time Around' is an interactive fiction/exploration game developed as a MSc final project. My responsibilities included game design (mechanics & aesthetics), narrative creation, programming using C# in Unity3D, sound design, QA, testing with users and analysing results, marketing the game, write a full report detailing the process of game development from research to final product.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Best Game Script Nominee (06/2018)

Nominated for a Writers' Guild of Ireland ZeBBie Award in Best Game Script as a co-writer of Simteractive's Eden Isle: Resort Paradise

LANGUAGES

English Native or Bilingual Proficiency Cantonese

Professional Working Proficiency

EDUCATION

MSc in Creative Digital Media

Dublin Institute of Technology

09/2013 - 02/2015

09/2009 - 07/2012

First Class Honours

BA (Hons) Journalism and Visual Media

Griffith College Dublin

First Class Honours

INTERESTS

Hiking

Gym

Videography

Gaming

Music

Travelling